YASH INDULKAR

yashindulkar31@gmail.com |+91-7400452552 | Mumbai, India 400067

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Pursuing Master of Science (MSc) from TCSC (University of Mumbai) in Information Technology, also working as IT Associate in ICICI Prudential Life Insurance under IT Customer & Distribution System, having a solid research background in areas such as CNN, Bayesian Deep Learning, GAN, Computational Linguistics. More broadly, inquisitive about NLP & Computer Vision with an approach to optimize and increase efficiency, speed & accuracy.

EDUCATION

Expected in Apr 2022

Master of Science: Information Technology

THAKUR COLLEGE OF SCIENCE & COMMERCE | Mumbai, India

Continuing education in MSc-IT Part II completed Part I with a 10/10 CGPA.

Oct 2020

Bachelor of Science: Information Technology

THAKUR COLLEGE OF SCIENCE & COMMERCE | Mumbai, India

Completed UG with 9.13/10 CGPA.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Jul 2020 - Current
IT Associate Manager
ICICI Prudential Life
Insurance Mumbai, IN

- Performed server backups and changed and replaced backup tapes daily along with database re-indexing.
- Patched software and installed new versions to eliminate security problems and protect data.
- Maintained servers and systems to keep networks fully operational during peak periods.
- Collaborated on 112 enhancements with 38 significant developments throughout different SDLC and maintained optimization of products.
- Used Microsoft SQL and Oracle SQL for firing queries, handling 17 different APIs, along with deploying various containers & schedulers.

May 2020 - Jul 2020 IT Intern ICICI Prudential Life

Insurance Mumbai. IN

- Supported team needs with system analysis, service requests, and communicative abilities.
- Analyzed & clarified computer user's problems with technical issues remotely and at workstations.

Collaborated on three enhancements related to OCR, SIT & API.

Aug 2018 - Dec 2019

Data Entry Expert

Sagar Dairy Farms

Mumbai, IN

- Compiled data and reviewed information for accuracy before input.
- Obtained scanned records and uploaded them into the database.
- Evaluated source documents to locate information needed for each data entry field.

PUBLICATIONS

Published in peer-reviewed journals & conferences

- 1. Y. Indulkar and A. Patil, "Sentiment Analysis of Uber & Ola using Deep Learning," 2020 International Conference on Smart Electronics and Communication (ICOSEC), Trichy, India, 2020, pp. 21-27.
- 2. J. Anthal, Y. Indulkar, A. Upadhyay, A. Patil, Twitter Sentimental Analysis & Algorithm Comparison for Uber & Ola Using 'R', Vol. 13 No. 1s (2020): Vol. 13 No. 1s (2020) Special Issue.
- 3. Anthal J., Upadhyay A., Patil A., Indulkar Y. (2021) Effects of Uber and Ola on SVM and Naïve Bayes. In: Second International Conference on Information Management and Machine Intelligence. Lecture Notes in Networks and Systems, vol 166. Springer, Singapore.
- 4. Y. Indulkar, "Time Series Analysis of Cryptocurrencies Using Deep Learning & Fbprophet," 2021 International Conference on Emerging Smart Computing and Informatics (ESCI), Pune, India, 2021, pp. 306-311.
- 5. Y. Indulkar, "PUBG Winner Ranking Prediction using R Interface 'h2o' Scalable Machine Learning Platform," 2021 International Conference on Emerging Smart Computing and Informatics (ESCI), Pune, India, 2021, pp. 300-305.
- 6. Y. Indulkar and A. Patil, "Comparative Study of Machine Learning Algorithms for Twitter Sentiment Analysis," 2021 International Conference on Emerging Smart Computing and Informatics (ESCI), 2021, pp. 295-299.
- 7. Y. Indulkar, "Alleviation of COVID by means of Social Distancing & Face Mask Detection Using YOLO V4," 2021 International Conference on Communication information and Computing Technology (ICCICT), 2021, pp. 1-8.
- 8. Indulkar, Yash, and Abhijit Patil. "Comparative Study for Neural Image Caption Generation Using Different Transfer Learning Along with Diverse Beam Search & Bi-Directional RNN," United International Journal for Research & Technology.

Under Publication manuscripts for journals

- 9. Indulkar, Yash, and Abhijit Patil, "Image Generation & Conversion to Super Resolution using Deep Convolutional GAN & Super Resolution GAN," submitted to International Journal of Scientific Engineering & Applied Science.
- 10. Indulkar, Yash, "Conditional Generative Adversarial Network to Generate Conditioned Images using MNIST Fashion Dataset," submitted to United International Journal for Research & Technology.

ARTICLES & STORIES SUBMITTED

Towards Data Science (TDS) a Medium Publication

- 1. Sentiment Analysis of Uber & Ola using Deep Learning
- 2. Twitter Sentiment Analysis & Algorithm Comparison for Uber & Ola using 'R'
- 3. Effects of Uber & Ola on SVM & Naïve Bayes
- 4. PUBG Winner Prediction using R Interface 'h2o' Scalable Machine Learning Platform

Analytics Vidya

5. Time Series Analysis of Cryptocurrencies using Deep Learning & Fbprophet

Analytics Vidya (Blogathon-8)

6. Alleviation of Covid by means of Social Distancing & Face Mask Detection using YOLO V4

PRESENTATIONS

Oral Presentations

- 1. Conference Presentation for International Conference on Computing technologies for Transforming the Automated World (ICCTAW-2020), Mumbai, India.
- 2. Conference Presentation for International Conference on Information Management & Machine Intelligence (ICIMMI-2020), Jaipur, India.
- 3. Conference Presentation for International conference on Smart Electronics and Communication (ICOSEC-2020), Trichy, India.
- 4. Conference Presentation for **3rd IEEE International Conference on Emerging Smart Computing and Informatics (ESCI-2021),** Pune, India.
- 5. Origin 2021 Presentation for **Thakur College of Science & Commerce (TCSC)** held by Department of Mathematics & Statistics.
- 6. Presentation for **Deep Learning Algorithms & Applications**, held by **Thakur College of Science & Commerce** for **AI is the Future** seminar, Mumbai, India.
- 7. Conference presentation for 2nd International Conference on Communication, Information and Computing Technology (ICCICT-2021), Mumbai, India.

GRANTS & AWARDS

- 1. Certificate of Merit Department of Mathematics and Statistics (TCSC) May 2021
- 2. **Won Best Paper of the Session** PUBG Winner Ranking Prediction using R Interface 'h2o' Scalable Machine Learning Platform March 2021
- 3. **Origin** 1st Prize for Information Technology Department in collaboration with science association March 2021
- 4. Certificate of Merit Department of Mathematics and statistics (TCSC) June 2020

- Won Kaggle Competition Using Computer Vision for Object Tracking with the help of YOLO July 2021
- 6. **Scholarship -** Awarded by Department of Information Technology (580 CAD) for Excellent Student FY 2019-2020.

PROFESSIONAL MEMBERSHIPS

- Analytics Vidya Creators Club
- IEEE Young Professionals
- IEEE Computational Intelligence Society
- IEEE Computer Society

CERTIFICATIONS

- Coursera Building Scalable Java Microservices with Spring Boot and Spring Cloud
- NPTEL Introduction to Machine Learning | IITKGP
- Aptech Enterprise Application Development in Java
- Skyfi Labs Machine Learning using Python

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Machine Learning
- Python/Scikit-learn
- Data Visualization

- Quantitative Analysis
- Oracle/SQL Server
- Data Warehouse/ETL

LINKS

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/yashindulkar/
- https://yashindulkar.github.io/
- https://yashindulkar.medium.com/

REFERENCES

Dr. S.K. Singh, Professor, and Head of Department

Department of Information Technology

Thakur College of Science & Commerce, University of Mumbai (+91) 9892434085, sksingh@tcsc.edu.in

Anand Upadhyay, Assistant Professor

Department of Information Technology
Thakur College of Science & Commerce, University of Mumbai
(+91) 9004113118, anandupadhyay@tcsc.edu.in

Jyotsna Anthal, Assistant Professor

Department of Information Technology

Thakur College of Science & Commerce, University of Mumbai (+91) 9867229559, jyotsnaanthal@tcsc.edu.in